Guide to the Printed Illustrations of Oxford and Oxfordshire Collection, approximately 1600-1908
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Printed Illustrations of Oxford and Oxfordshire Collection
approximately 1600-1908
3.5 cubic feet (8 boxes, 1 framed item)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Collection of printed illustrations of Oxford and Oxfordshire.
Scope and Content Note
A collection of printed illustrations depicting Oxfordshire and the city of Oxford in England.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Places:
Oxford (England); Oxfordshire (England)
Document Types:
Lithographs; Prints (visual works)
VCL Categories:
Art and Artists
Encoding Information
Encoded by Mark Seidl, May 2021. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, July 2023.
Acquisition Information
Source unknown.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series and arranged alphabetically by title within each series.
Series List
- Series I. Maps and Views of Oxford
- Series II. Oxford Street Views
- Series III. Oxford Buildings
- Series IV. People and Events at Oxford
- Series V. Nearby Locations
- Series VI. Miscellaneous
Container List
- SERIES I. MAPS AND VIEWS OF OXFORD
  - Oxford, from a field in China Lane, approximately 1820 (2.36)
  - Oxford, from … Bagley Wood, 1820 (2.33)
  - … Oxford, from Heddington Hill, undated (5.59)
  - Oxford, from the Henley Road, 1821 (2.31)
  - [Oxford, from the Observatory], undated (1.8)
  - Oxford, from … the Path to Pullin’s Tree, 1822 (2.35)
  - … Oxford, from Wytham, 1848 (5.58)
  - Oxford, [North View], 1821 (2.34)
  - [Oxford, map], undated (2.32)
  - [Oxford, map], undated (6.1)
  - [Oxford, SE View], undated (2.28)
  - [Oxford, SE View], undated (2.30)
  - [Oxford (two views)], undated (5.62)
  - [Oxford (two views)], undated (5.63)
  - [Oxford (two views)], undated (5.65)
  - [Oxford, various views], undated (5.47)
  - Untitled view, undated (5.3)
  - Untitled view, undated (6.9)
  - [View from Christ Church Meadow], undated (7.26)
  - View from the Grounds at the North East of Wadham College, 1848 (5.51)
  - Way, Thomas, "The Towers of Oxford from the Bell Tower of Magdalen College," lithograph, 1908 Nov 5; [1 framed print] (Framed Storage 2.6)
- SERIES II. OXFORD STREET VIEWS
  - South East View of the Taylor Building and University Galleries, 1847 (4.44)
  - Broad Street, undated (3.1)
  - Carfax Conduit…, 1820 (4.64)
  - Cat Street, Hertford College, 1820 (2.48)
  - Entrance to Oxford …, undated (2.29)
  - … Entrance to Oxford, 1816 (5.61)
  - [Fleigh Street], undated (1.4)
  - …Folly Bridge…, 1853 (4.63)
  - High Street, undated (1.6a)
  - High Street, 1811 (8.1)
  - [High Street, Carfax Conduit], undated (4.9)
  - Hithe Bridge, etc., 1817 (4.51)
  - Hythe Bridge with Tower of the Castle, undated (4.65)
  - Magdalen Bridge…, 1819 (4.35)
  - Magdalen Tower and Bridge…, 1854 (4.62)
  - Magpie Lane, undated (4.13)
  - Martyrs Memorial, 1842 (2.27)
  - [North Gate], undated (5.57)
  - [Perspective View]: Cathedral and Radcliffe Library, undated (4.2)
  - [Perspective View]: Radcliffe Library, Brazen Nose College, undated (2.10)
  - [Perspective View]: Radcliffe Library, All Souls College, undated (2.25)
  - [Perspective View: Radcliffe Library, All Souls’ College…], undated (4.55)
  - [Perspective View]: [Printing House, Theater, the Museum, various colleges], undated (3.13)
  - [Perspective View]: Printing House, Theater…, undated (4.40)
  - [Perspective View, Colleges]: Baliol College, Trinity College…, undated (5.41)
  - [Perspective View, Colleges, from The Turl], approximately 1806 (6.16)
  - Perspective View [Colleges]: Exter, Alban, Hart, Edmund, Mary, Merton, Brazen Nose, New Inn, Magdalen, Worcester, undated (7.27)
  - [Perspective View, Colleges]: New and Magdalen, undated (4.3)
  - [Perspective View, Colleges]: Merton and Christ Church, undated (7.20)
  - [Perspective View, Colleges]: Oriel and Corpus Christi Colleges, undated (3.17)
  - [Perspective View, Colleges]: Queens College, University College, All Souls College…, undated (4.25)
  - Perspective View [Colleges]: Queens College, University College, All Souls College…, undated (2.8)
  - [Perspective View Colleges]: St. Mary’s Church, All Saints’ Church…, undated (4.41)
  - The Turl, 1820 (2.15)
  - [Untitled view], undated (5.67)
- SERIES III. OXFORD BUILDINGS
  - All Saints Church, undated (5.14)
  - [All Souls College, atrium], 1717 (8.2)
  - [All Souls College, atrium], [1717?] (8.4)
  - [All Souls College,] Ichnographia, undated (8.3)
  - [All Souls College, Library], undated (7.2)
  - [All Souls College], Mallardianorum effigies …, undated (4.7)
  - All Souls College, The New Quadrangle, undated (2.3)
  - Balliol College, undated (2.24)
  - Balliol College, undated (3.27)
  - [Balliol College], undated (5.9)
  - [Balliol College, New Chapel], undated (4.54)
  - [Balliol College, Plan], undated (6.5)
  - [Balliol College, South East View], undated (6.6)
  - Bodleian Library, undated (4.15)
  - [Bodleian Library, interior], undated (5.24)
  - [Bodleian Library, interior], undated (7.28)
  - [Bodleian Library, picture gallery], 1829 (7.40)
  - [Brasen Nose College], undated (4.26)
  - [Brasen Nose College, Front], 1816 (3.29)
  - [Brasen Nose College, Front], undated (7.46)
  - [Brasen Nose College, the Large Quadrangle], undated (1.9a)
  - [Brasen Nose College, Plan,], undated (7.12)
  - Chapter House, undated (4.18)
  - [Christ Church, Canterbury Gate], after 1775 (5.38)
  - [Christ Church], Cathedral, undated (3.28)
  - [Christ Church, Cathedral], undated (5.52)
  - … Christ Church, Cathedral, undated (7.45)
  - [Christ Church, Cathedral and Chapterhouse], undated (5.53)
  - [Christ Church, Cathedral, St. Friedeswide’s Chapel], undated (6.7)
  - [Christ Church, Cathedral, St. Friedeswide’s Chapel], after 1790 (6.8)
  - Christ Church Cathedral, [interior], 1816 (5.26)
  - Christ Church from the Gardens, undated (4.11)
  - Christ Church from the Meadows, 1816 (4.39)
  - [Christ Church, Front View], undated (6.11)
  - [Christ Church, Great Quadrangle], undated (3.10)
  - [Christ Church, Inside View of the Hall], undated (7.49)
  - Christ Church, Kitchen, undated (4.19)
  - Christ Church, Library, undated (2.52)
  - Christ Church, Library, undated (4.68)
  - [Christ Church, New Gate], [1785?] (5.37)
  - [Christ Church, New Quadrangle], undated (7.7)
  - [Christ Church, New Quadrangle], undated (7.8)
  - [Christ Church, Old Stables and Remains of Austin Friary], 1821 (5.69)
  - [Christ Church], plan of the building destroyed by the Fire, 1809 (3.6)
  - [Christ Church, Staircase Leading to the Hall], undated (6.10)
  - [Christ Church, Tom Gate], undated (2.40)
  - Christ Church, Walk, 1822 (2.47)
  - [Christ Church, West Front], 1820 (5.66)
  - [Christ Church] West Entrance from Pembroke Lane, undated (5.68)
  - [Christ Church, Wide Walk], 1820 (2.41)
  - [Corpus Christi College], undated (4.30)
  - [Corpus Christi College], undated (5.39)
  - [Corpus Christi College, facades and plans], undated (7.16)
  - [Corpus Christi College, facade and quadrangle], 1832 (1.6b)
  - Corpus Christi College from the Fields, undated (4.56)
  - Corpus Christi College, the Fellows’ Building, undated (2.18)
  - Coventry Hall, 1819 (5.33)
  - [Divinity School, interior], undated (4.23)
  - Exeter College, undated (3.22)
  - [Exeter College], undated (4.27)
  - … Friar Bacon’s Study, 1819 (5.17)
  - … Friar Bacon’s Study, undated (7.24)
  - [Hertford College,] Demolished Buildings…, 1822 (5.43)
  - [Herford College, facade], undated (7.37)
  - Hertford College from the Grove, undated (5.3)
  - [Jesus College], undated (5.6)
  - [Jesus College], undated (6.15)
  - Jesus College, Chapel, undated (3.23)
  - Lincoln College, undated (3.21)
  - [Lincoln College], undated (4.28)
  - [Lincoln College], [1723?] (6.17)
  - Lincoln [College], Chapel, undated (3.20)
  - Little Lion Hall and Great Lion Hall, 1817 (5.60)
  - [Magdalen College], 1823 (1.3)
  - Magdalen College, undated (2.6)
  - Magdalen College, undated (4.17)
  - …Magdalen College…, undated (4.57)
  - [Magdalen College], undated (5.5)
  - Magdalen College…, [1778?] (4.48)
  - Magdalen College, New Building, undated (2.54)
  - [Magdalen College, New Hall], undated (1.1a)
  - [Magdalen College, Old Approach], 1846 (4.60)
  - [Magdalen College, Plan], undated (7.14)
  - [Magdalen College, Quadrangle], undated (4.59)
  - [Magdalen College], Remains of Old Magdalen Hall, 1841 (4.58)
  - [Magdalen College], Tower, undated (2.2)
  - Merton [College], undated (4.20)
  - [Merton College], undated (5.4)
  - [Merton College], undated (7.34)
  - [Merton College], undated (7.35)
  - …Merton College, Chapel, [1802?] (7.17)
  - Merton College, Chapel…, 1820 (7.19)
  - [Merton College, Entrance], undated (1.9b)
  - [Merton College, Demolished Buildings], 1821 (4.50)
  - Merton College from the Grove, undated (4.49)
  - Merton College from the Meadows, undated (2.43)
  - [Merton College, Plan], undated (7.18)
  - [Natural History Museum], undated; (photograph) (4.72)
  - [New College] …, undated (2.44)
  - [New College], undated (7.13)
  - [New College], undated (7.15)
  - [New College], undated (7.31)
  - [New College], [1674?] (7.33)
  - [New College], undated (7.47)
  - [New College, Chapel and Tower], 1843 (5.16)
  - New College, from the Mount, undated (2.20)
  - [Observatory], undated (2.26)
  - Old Buildings…, 1821 (5.32)
  - Old Carfax Church, 1819 (2.38)
  - [Oriel College, New Library], 1741 (7.30)
  - [Oxford] Castle…, undated (2.37)
  - [Oxford Castle, Crypt], 1820 (5.18)
  - [Oxford Castle, Tower], 1818 (5.45)
  - …Pembroke College, 1837 (5.64)
  - [Pembroke College, New Hall], 1857 (5.70)
  - [Queen’s College], 1751 (1.1b)
  - [Queen’s College], 1751 (2.12)
  - [Queen’s College], undated (4.16)
  - [Queen’s College], undated (5.8)
  - … Queen’s College, undated (7.50)
  - [Queen’s College, Old Buildings], 1818 (5.21)
  - [Queen’s College, Plan], undated (7.1)
  - [Queen’s College, room of the Black Prince], 1751 (4.8)
  - [Radcliffe Camera], undated (1.5)
  - Radcliffe [Camera]…, undated (3.30)
  - [Radcliffe Camera], undated (4.24)
  - [Radcliffe Camera], undated (5.13)
  - [Radcliffe Camera], undated (7.29)
  - [Radcliffe Camera], Interior, 1835 (4.21)
  - [Radcliffe Camera, plan], 1737 (5.22)
  - [Sheldonian Theatre], Nummorum antiquorum scriniis Bodelianis reconditorum cataologus, 1750 (3.2)
  - [Sheldonian Theatre], undated (5.7)
  - [Sheldonian Theatre], undated (7.6)
  - [Sheldonian Theatre], undated (7.9)
  - [Sheldonian Theatre], undated (7.11)
  - [Sheldonian Theatre, façade and plan], undated (3.15)
  - [St. Aldale’s], undated (3.12)
  - [St. Alban Hall], undated (4.31)
  - [St.] Alban Hall, undated (4.32)
  - [St. Alban Hall, plan], undated (7.36)
  - St. Clement’s Church, 1836 (5.15)
  - [St. Ebbe, Old Church], 1818 (5.56)
  - St. Edmund Hall, 1822 (1.7a)
  - St. Edmund Hall, undated (2.9)
  - [St. Edmund Hall], undated (4.22)
  - [St. Edmund Hall], undated; [See also: St. Peter in the East (now St. Edmund Hall library)] (3.19)
  - St. Giles’ Church, undated (2.4)
  - …St Giles’ Church, 1845 (5.28)
  - [St. John’s College], 1828 (2.49)
  - St. John’s College, undated (3.26)
  - [St. John’s College], undated (5.2)
  - St. John’s College…, [1783?] (5.23)
  - [St. John’s College, Canterbury Quad], undated (7.32)
  - [St. John’s College, Interior Quadrangle], 1844 (5.48)
  - St. John’s College … Library …, 1828 (2.50)
  - … St. Martin’s Church, 1820 (4.37)
  - St. Mary Hall, undated (2.14,)
  - St. Mary Hall, undated (4.14)
  - [St. Mary Hall], undated (4.29)
  - [St. Mary Hall, Church], undated (2.13)
  - St. Mary [Hall], Church, undated (3.16)
  - [St. Mary Hall, Church], undated (5.40)
  - St. Mary Magdalen Church, 1820 (2.23)
  - [St. Mary Magdalen Church], 1839 (4.69)
  - [St. Mary Magdalen College], undated (7.48)
  - [St. Peter in the East], undated; (see also: St. Edmund Hall) (3.24)
  - St. Peter in the East, undated (4.42)
  - St. Peter … in the East, 1820 (4.52)
  - … St. Peter [in the East], undated (7.23)
  - … St. Peter in the East, undated (7.25)
  - Cryprt of St. Peter's Church in the East, approximately 1822 (4.4)
  - Trinity College, undated (2.7)
  - Trinity College…, undated (4.46)
  - [Trinity College], 1688 (5.1)
  - [Trinity College], undated (7.4)
  - Trinity College, President’s Lodgings, undated (2.21)
  - … University College …, 1823 (5.19)
  - University Printing House, 1832 (5.44)
  - Untitled photograph, undated (4.61)
  - Untitled view, undated (1.2)
  - Untitled view, undated; (same as 1.2) (2.1)
  - Untitled view, undated; (same as 1.2) (2.5)
  - Untitled view, undated (2.17)
  - Untitled view, 1809 (3.3)
  - Untitled view, 1809 (3.4)
  - Untitled view, 1809 (3.5)
  - Untitled view, 1809 (3.7)
  - Untitled view, 1809 (3.8)
  - Untitled view, 1809 (3.9)
  - Untitled view, 1809 (3.11)
  - Untitled view, undated (4.43)
  - Untitled view, undated (4.53)
  - Untitled View, [1798?] (4.66)
  - Untitled view, undated (5.12)
  - Untitled view, undated (5.27)
  - Untitled view, undated (5.46)
  - Untitled view [chapel], undated (4.6)
  - [Various Oxford Buildings], undated (4.47)
  - [Various Oxford Buildings] (5.10)
  - Wadham College …, undated (2.51)
  - [Wadham College], undated (7.3)
  - Wadham College…, undated (7.10)
  - [Wadham College], undated (7.39)
  - [Wadham College], undated (7.42)
  - Wadham [College], Chapel …, undated (2.53)
  - Wadham College, Grounds, 1848 (5.51)
  - Wackham Chapel, undated (3.25)
  - Worcester College, undated (2.11)
  - Worcester College…, 1855 (4.36)
  - [Worcester College], undated (6.12)
  - [Worcester College], undated (6.13)
  - [Worcester College], undated (6.14)
  - [Worcester College, New Buildings], undated (2.46)
  - [Worcester College, Old Buildings], undated (2.45)
- SERIES IV. PEOPLE AND EVENTS AT OXFORD
  - The board walk, Christ Church Meadows, Oxford, on Sunday Evening, June 16th, undated; [newspaper clipping] (2.19)
  - [Capriccio], [1765?] (5.49)
  - [Capriccio], undated (5.50)
  - English Agricultural Society’s Dinner … 1839 (4.5)
  - [English Agricultural Society’s Dinner, 1839] (4.34)
  - [English Agricultural Society’s Dinner, 1839] (4.71)
  - [English Agricultural Society’s Dinner,1839] (5.20)
  - Henley Regata, June 1844 (2.16)
  - [Procession], undated (6.2)
  - … Thames Regata, undated (3.18)
- SERIES V. NEARBY LOCATIONS
  - [Antiquy Hall], 1817 (5.55)
  - Bathing Place, undated (2.39)
  - … Beaumont, 1819 (5.25)
  - Blenheim House, undated (5.42)
  - [Clattercote-Priory, SW View], undated (4.45)
  - [Hedington Hill, Joe Pullen’s Elm], 1821 (4.67)
  - Iffley Mill, undated (2.22)
  - Village of Iffley …, approximately 1840 (4.10)
  - … Nuneham, 1787 (7.41)
  - …Osney Abbey, 1817 (5.35)
  - …Rewley Abbey…, 1818 (5.34)
  - [Stanton-Hancourt, Ruins, Chapel], 1763 (7.43)
  - [Stanton-Hancourt, Ruins, Chapel], [1763?] (7.44)
  - [Stanton-Hancourt, Ruins, Kitchens], 1785 (7.21)
  - [Stanton-Hancourt, Ruins, Kitchens and offices], 1763 (6.4)
  - Yeofley, Church, undated (7.22)
- SERIES VI. MISCELLANEOUS
  - [Ashmolean Museum, marbles], undated (3.14)
  - [1 Chron. xxix. 11 and Luke ii.14 in various languages], 1814; [Type specimen sheet of the Clarendon Press, Oxford] (4.33)
  - Fonts at Oxford Churches, 1821 (5.31)
  - Illustration for Concert at Sheldonian Theatre, 1818 (1.7b)
  - Praefatio, undated; [Leaf from catalogue of printed books at the Bodleian Library(?)] (4.70)
  - Pictorial Times, [Oxford Grand Comemoration, 1844], approximately 1844 (6.3)
  - Pictorial Times (View of Oxford), undated (4.38)
  - Pictorial Times (Views of Oxford), undated (5.11)
  - Pictorial Times (Views of Oxford), undated (5.29)
  - Pictorial Times (Views of Oxford; Oxford People), undated (5.30)
  - References to the Plates; References to the Ground Plan, undated (2.42)
  - [Roundel], undated (4.12)
  - Specimen of the Decoration of Rooms in the reign of Q. Elizabeth, 1823 (5.54)
  - Untitled interior view “Sciant psentes fut…,", undated (4.1)
  - [Various clippings], undated; [The Academical Habits of the several degrees in the University of Oxford; The conservatory for ever-greens in the Physick Garden of the University of Oxford; Scholae Publicae; The Grand Entrance of Christ Church; East Side of the Quadrangle of the Schools; Vue du theatre de Sheldon à Oxford, du côté du Nord] (7.5)
  - Untitled view and scene, undated (7.38)